Fossieck, Theodore; Papers ua902.032
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Thoedore Fossieck Papers1947-1996
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Fossieck, Theodore
ua902.032
3.66 cubic ft.
This collection contains some administrative materials related to the running of the school, as well as information on class reunions, and copies of the yearbook Bricks and Ivy.
Acquisition Information
All items in this record group were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Theodore Fossieck.
Biographical History
Theodore Fossieck was the principal of Milne from 1948-1972, and therefore, spanned many years as the chief administrator. He was very active in school functions and was liked by the students, based on his presence at many school reunions after the closing of Milne. He retired in 1972, amidst the pressure on the school to accept more diverse applicants, as well as severe budget cuts in the SUNY system that would lead to the closing of the Milne school in 1977.
Even after his departure as principal, Fossieck remained active among the Milne School Alumni. He atteneded many reunions, along with other faculty members, and kept in tocuh with many students. He retained many student records such as class rankings and yearbooks. Fossieck remained in Albany helping to preserve local history as a member of the Board of Trustees for the Albany County Historical Society.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials donated by Dr. Theodroe Fossieck, former principal of The Milne School from 1948-1972. In it are materials not directly related to the administration of the school, but dealing more with events after his resignation from the position of principal. Donated were select copies of the yearbook, "Bricks and Ivy," dating between 1947 and 1977, as well as student file cards containing names of past students and their former home addreses. Many of them are undated, but those that are date to Fossieck's years as principal from 1948-1972.
The last piece donated are the files Fossieck kept related to the various reunions of Milne Alumni that he attended. Each file contains materials such as invitations, newsletters reporting the status of former class members, as well as the class ranking of each group along with their GPA.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into three series, each arranged topically.
Access
Access to the Student File Cards (Series 1) and much of the Milne Alumni Material (Series2) is restricted due to the presence of student grades and personal information. Please contact the University Archivist about accessing this material.
Albany, New York; Education; Education, Secondary; School Principals; UAlbany Faculty & Alumni Papers
- Student File Cards, 1948-1971, Undated; 1; 2.0 cubic ft.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted due to the presence of student grades. These records cannot be made available due to the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please consult an archivist for more details.
  Arrangement
  This collection is arragned chronologically, and within that arrangement, alphabetically by the last name of the student.
  Scope and Contents
  This series is made up of index cards with former students names and addresses on them.
  - Student File Cards A-Q, 1950-1971 (Box 1 (1-Student File Cards), Folder 1)
  - Student File Cards R-Z, 1950-1971 (Box 1 (1-Student File Cards), Folder 2)
  - Student File Cards, 1948-1962 (Box 1 (1-Student File Cards), Folder 3)
  - Student File Cards A-D, Undated (Box 2 (1-Student File Cards), Folder 1)
  - Student File Cards E-J, Undated (Box 2 (1-Student File Cards), Folder 2)
  - Student File Cards K-O, Undated (Box 2 (1-Student File Cards), Folder 3)
  - Student File Cards P-S, Undated (Box 2 (1-Student File Cards), Folder 4)
  - Student File Cards T-Z, Undated (Box 2 (1-Student File Cards), Folder 5)
- Milne Alumni Material, 1951-1996; 2; 0.66 cubic ft.
  Some material in this series is restricted due to the presence of student grades and other personal information. These records cannot be made available due to the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please consult an archivist for more details.
  Materials are arranged in the original order they were found in.
  Series is made up of material collected by Dr. Fossieck related to class reunions, as well as obituaries for former students and faculty.
  - Photographs of Milne Murals, Undated (Box 3 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 1)
  - Program for 1994 Reunion of Classes 1953, 1954, and 1955 (Box 3 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 2)
  - Milne Alumni List, 1994 (Box 3 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 3)
  - 1991 Reunion Bricks and Ivy (Box 3 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 4)
  - Proposal to Renovate Milne Room, 1994 (Box 3 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 5)
  - Milne Alumni Campaign, 1993 (Box 3 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 6)
  - Milne Alumni Campaign, 1993 (Box 3 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 7)
  - Milne Alumni Campaign, 1993 (Box 3 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 8)
  - Milne Alumni Campaign, 1993 (Box 3 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 9)
  - Class of 1946 Reunion Planning, 1981 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 1)
  - Class of 1947 and 1948 Class Rankings, 1983 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 2)
  - Class of 1949 Reunion, 1964 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 3)
  - Class of 1950 Reunion Planning, 1976 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 4)
  - Class of 1951 Reunion, 1981 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 5)
  - Class of 1952 25th Reunion, 1977 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 6)
  - Class of 1953 Ranking and Home Addresses, 1983-1993 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 7)
  - Class of 1954 Ranking and Class List, Undated (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 8)
  - Class of 1955 Ranking and Newsletter, 1975 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 9)
  - Class of 1956 Reunion and Newsletter, 1976-1988 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 10)
  - Class of 1957-1958 Ranking (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 11)
  - Class of 1959 Reunion and Newsletter, 1984 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 12)
  - Class of 1960 Ranking and Locator, 1985 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 13)
  - Class of 1961 Reunion Planning, 1981 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 14)
  - Class of 1962 and 1964 Ranking (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 15)
  - Class of 1965 and 1966 Reunion and Ranking, 1990 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 16)
  - Class of 1967 Reunion, 1977-1987 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 17)
  - Class of 1968 Class List (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 18)
  - Class of 1969 and 1970 Ranking, 1969-1970 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 19)
  - Class of 1971 and 1972 Reunion and Ranking, 1971-1976 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 20)
  - Class of 1973 Reunion, 1983 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 21)
  - Class of 1975 Ranking (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 22)
  - Classes of 1976 and 1977 Ranking and Commencement, 1976-1977 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 23)
  - Schoolwide Reunion, 1991 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 24)
  - Alumni Ball Register, 1951-1977 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 25)
  - Faculty and Alumni Obituaries, 1993 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 26)
  - Faculty and Alumni Obituaries, 1993-1996 (Box 4 (2-Milne Alumni Material), Folder 27)
- Bricks and Ivy, 1947-1977; 3; 1.0 cubic ft.
  Materials are arranged in chronological order.
  This series is made up of Bricks and Ivy Yearbooks donated by Dr. Fossieck.
  - Bricks and Ivy, 1947 (Box 5 (3-Bricks and Ivy), Folder 1)
  - Bricks and Ivy, 1948 (Box 5 (3-Bricks and Ivy), Folder 2)
  - Bricks and Ivy, 1949 (Box 5 (3-Bricks and Ivy), Folder 3)
  - Bricks and Ivy, 1951 (Box 5 (3-Bricks and Ivy), Folder 4)
  - Bricks and Ivy, 1952 (Box 5 (3-Bricks and Ivy), Folder 5)
  - Bricks and Ivy, 1953 (Box 5 (3-Bricks and Ivy), Folder 6)
  - Bricks and Ivy, 1957 (Box 5 (3-Bricks and Ivy), Folder 7)
  - Bricks and Ivy, 1958 (Box 5 (3-Bricks and Ivy), Folder 8)
  - Bricks and Ivy, 1963 (Box 5 (3-Bricks and Ivy), Folder 9)
  - Bricks and Ivy, 1967 (Box 5 (3-Bricks and Ivy), Folder 10)
  - Bricks and Ivy, 1971 (Box 5 (3-Bricks and Ivy), Folder 11)
  - Bricks and Ivy, 1977 (Box 5 (3-Bricks and Ivy), Folder 12)